<resume>
  <name>Li Zhong </name>
  <profile>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <birthday>Jun. 2, 1983</birthday>
    <telephone>15902198964</telephone>
    <email>phenicsl@gmail.com</email>
    <experience>1.5 years</experience>
  </profile>
  <academy>
    <duration>
      <from>2005</from>
      <to>2008</to>
      <degree>Master</degree>
      <major>System Architecture</major>
      <school>Xi'an Jiaotong University</school>
    </duration>
    <duration>
      <from>2001</from>
      <to>2005</to>
      <degree>Bachelor</degree>
      <major>Computer Science</major>
      <school>Xi'an Jiaotong University</school>
    </duration>
  </academy>
  <history>
    <job>
      <duration>
	<from>Aug. 2008</from>
	<to>Present</to>
      </duration>
      <organization>EMC China R&amp;D center</organization>
      <title>Software Engineer</title>
      <projects>
	<project>
	  <name>
	  Platypus Hardware Diagnostic Application
	  </name>
	  <description>
	    Initial member to start up the development of Platypus Diagnostic
	    Application, which is the next generation diagnostic software for
	    EMC storage platforms. Worked in following fields:
	  </description>
	  <taskset>
	    <task>
	      <title>
		Zeroconf Service Discovery and File Transfer Implementation
	      </title>	     
	      <keywords>
		C, Pthread, Zeroconf Protocol, Asynchronous Programming, Linux Socket Programming, Regular Expression
	      </keywords>
	      <responsibility>
		<item>
		  Took ownership to investigate Zeroconf protocol and share
		  knowledge with team members. Designed Zeroconf service
		  registration and discovery implementation proposal.
		</item>
		<item>
		  Implemented Zeroconf service register for diagnostic service
		  publication and service browser for service discovery. 
		</item>
		<item>
		  C/S model socket programming on Linux system to implement file transfer protocol. 
		</item>
		<item>
		  Used regular expression to parse file transfer request command and response.
		</item>
		<item>
		  Pthread and asynchronous programming was used to support Zeroconf service discovery.
		</item>
	      </responsibility>
	    </task>
	    <task>
	      <title>Atomic Tests Implementation</title> 
	      <keywords>C++, Boost, libusb, SCSI, SATA</keywords>
	      <responsibility>
		<item>
		  Implement atomic tests for discovered devices. It involved
		  test logic implementation, physical device access and
		  input/output operations.
		</item>
		<item>
		  Investigated USB Mass Storage and SCSI protocol. 
		  Implemented read/write, get_capacity operations.
		</item>
		<item>
  		  Implemented SATA device atomic tests that provide SATA device read/write,
		  display S.M.A.R.T, identify operations.
		</item>
		<item>
		  Boost libraries was used to handle device information and input/output.
		</item>
	      </responsibility>
	    </task>
	    <task>
	      <title>Construction Algorithm and Builder</title>
	      <keywords>C/C++, Boost::Spirit, libxml++</keywords>
	      <responsibility>
		<item>
		  Worked as maintainer for Construction &amp; Builder sub system.
		</item>
		<item>
		  Maintain and improve construction algorithm which involves XML
		  file parsing(libxml++), expression parsing(Boost::Spirit) and
		  complex match algorithm.
		</item>
		<item>
		  Worked as git sub system maintainer for code quality and
		  version control process assurance.
		</item>
		<item>
		  Implemented logger library that supports difference categories and levels.
		</item>
	      </responsibility>
	    </task>
	  </taskset>
	</project>
      </projects>
    </job>
    <job>
      <duration>
	<from>Mar. 2006</from>
	<to>Jul. 2008</to>
      </duration>
      <organization>NHPCC</organization>
      <title>Master Student</title>
      <projects>
      <project>
	<name>Prophet Speculative Multi-threading (SpMT) Technology</name>
	<description>
	  Key researcher in "Prophet" project, which focus on compiler
	  and architecture technology for Thread-Level Speculation on multi-core
	  processor. Worked in following tasks:
	</description>
	<taskset>
	  <task>
	    <title>Intermediate Instruction Virtual Machine for SpMT Architecture</title>
	    <keywords>SpMT architecture, Virtual Machine, Interpreter</keywords>
	    <responsibility>
	      <item> 
		Designed speculative execution model and SpMT architecture with
		a new Cache structure to solve dependence violation.
	      </item>
	      <item> 
		Crafted SpMT virtual machine to simulate SpMT architecture by
		interpreting compiled intermediate instructions.
	      </item>
	    </responsibility>
	  </task>	  
	  <task>
	    <title>Thread Partition Algorithm Research</title>
	    <keywords>compiler infrastructure, data flow analysis, thread partition algorithm</keywords>
	    <responsibility>
	      <item>
		Design and implement thread partition algorithm to explore
		thread-level parallel of natural loops.
	      </item>
	      <item>
		Data flow analysis programming experience based on SUIF compiler infrastructure.
	      </item>
	    </responsibility>
	  </task>
	</taskset>
      </project>
      </projects>
    </job>
  </history>
  
  <skillset>
    <skill>
      <title>Languages</title>
      <description>
	C/C++, Java, Python, Bash, XML, HTML, Elisp
      </description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <description>
	GNU development tool set(GCC, Gmake, GDB), Emacs, Eclipse, Git, Mysql
      </description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <title>
	Technology Skills
      </title>
      <description>
	<item>
	  Proficiency with C/C++ programming. Familiar with Java, Python.
	</item>
	<item>
	  Solid knowledge on compiler principle, have knowledge about parser,
	  interpreter implementation.
	</item>
	<item>
	  Solid knowledge on Linux system usage. Familiar with Bash script
	  programming. Advanced Pthread and multi-threading programming
	  knowledge.
	</item>
	<item>
	  Good knowledge about Object-oriented design, design pattern and UML.
	</item>
	<item>
	  In depth experience with  Linux socket programming. Familiar with TCP/IP network protocol.
	</item>	
	<item>
	  Good knowledge about markup languages. Familiar with HTML, XML, XSLT,
	  XSL-FO. Have knowledge about CSS and Javascript.
	</item>
	<item>
	  Some experiences with using Servlet, GWT, Spring and Hibernate. Have
	  basic knowledge about dynamic web application development.
	</item>
	<item>
	  Have experience with elisp programming for Emacs extension writting.
	</item>
      </description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <title>English</title>
      <description>
	Fluent English
      </description>
    </skill>
  </skillset>

  <awards>
    <award>
      <time>
	<year>2009</year>
      </time>
      <description>
	"Bronze Medal of Recognition" award by EMC R &amp; D Center
      </description>
    </award>
  </awards>
</resume>